# **Yigit Mersin**

## FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

I'm a former technical customer support executive and a web developer who is currently studying in a global full-stack development school called Microverse and performed forefront supervisor roles in various industries.

I can adapt to different industries and my goal is to create value for your organization by combining my business, customer support, and software development experience to create better service for your business.

## **EXPERIENCE**

British Consulate of General, Istanbul, Turkey

Data Entry Clerk | May 2017 - September 2019

- I gained working experience in a diverse workplace and delivered data entry tasks in requested standards.
- I provided support for desktop tool usage: e.g.; excel, outlook; which helped to decrease the IT department's workload.

FLYCO e-Learning Solutions, *Istanbul*, *Turkey* 

Support Team Manager | March 2017 - February 2019

- Led support team which helped me to gain hands-on experience in a global SaaS start-up and improved my communication & management
- Provided reports/lists according to customer needs which helped me to learn foundations for SQL & Postgresql.

Arkhe Software Technologies, *Istanbul, Turkey* 

Software Support Agent | November 2016 - March 2017

- Provided remote customer support over the weekends and during night shifts which helped improve after-sales services and fulfill 24/7 customer support needs.
- Experienced in the hardware & software integration processes between dummy terminal machines, pos devices with central web software.

#### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE | May 2020 - Present

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- I spend almost 1300+ hours; mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development. Simultaneously I am developing projects with JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, and Rails.
- I developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

BASKENT UNIVERSITY | September 2003 – June 2008

Faculty of Commercial Sciences, Tourism & Hotel Management

- Studied the theoretical commercial science curriculum.
- Part-time & full-time internships and work experiences in the tourism industry.

**Portfolio** Github | Linkedin vigitmitmersin@gmail.com

**SKILLS** 

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript

Back-end: Ruby, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Webpack, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD basics, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, GitFlow, Scrum Habits

**PROJECTS** 

#### **Covid-19 Tracking App**

- Users can search & display statistics via Narrativa API - Built with: Javascript, React & Redux, Thunk, Bootstrap.

### **React Group Project**

- Web app with SpaceX API by using GitHub kanban board with git-flow practices.
- Built with: Javascript, React & Redux, Bootstrap.

#### **TV Guide**

- Group project aims to build a TV guide with REST actions.
- Built with: Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Webpack.

#### **CSS Linter**

- A command-line CSS rule checker with OOP & Ruby.
- Built with: Ruby